+370 68366381

vaidas.bizokas@gmail.com

SUMMARY

I am a financial professional with 15+ years of experience in business planning, management consulting, product and process insight. I am result oriented person, family men, technology buff, stock investor, responsible and capable of working with tight deadlines.

EXPERIENCE

SIG, Head of Financial Controlling and Analysis

2022

 Lead financial analysis, KPI, CF, workflow processes, POC, budget planning and funding, working with team

Tele2, Chief Economist 2003-2022

- Tele2 is the mobile communications leader in Lithuania and in terms of number of customers, revenues, EBITDA and net profit. Since 2003 until 2020 Tele2's mobile revenue share grew from 15% to 42%, Tele2 have a very strong brand recognition and has the largest market share in postpaid residential and prepaid segments, with rapid growth in business, MBB and M2M.
- Annual financial planning process with quarterly updates and presentations to management, providing in deep finance and accounting analysis to achieve targets and KPI settings
- Analysis and insights of competitive market environment, working with marketing and product team to develop price plans and product strategy, I consulted on issues on consumption, cost and income drivers
- I implemented the system and was responsible for the accuracy and completeness of interconnect minutes, P2P SMS, A2P SMS reports and invoices with other operators
- During the crisis, competitions for the best ideas were held several times among all employees, I won
 1st and 4th place

Alterna Invest, Bank Snoras, Lietuvos Energija (Ignitis)

1999-2003

 Accounting, analysis of fixed income and equity investment, communication with Securities Commission, banks, shareholders, risk management and I have a broker license

EDUCATION

Vilnius University (Lithuania)

Master's degree, Laser and Optical Technology

CERTIFICATES

CFA Institute (US)

Chartered Financial Analyst (CFA)

ADDITIONAL SKILLS

- Challenges the status quo, business process improvement & strategic development, statistical models, multiple regression & correlation, assess brand performance, SWOT, conjoint analysis, price elasticity, working capital & cash flow calculation, problem solving
- Handle large data and extract key information using SQL, Tableau, Hadoop, Access, Excel, SharePoint
- Metrics, high-quality strategic projects, sensitivity & risk, research & benchmarks, commission fee structures & incentive systems, segmentation
- · Equity investment using multivariate analysis
- I decided to leave a comfort zone and take on a new challenge
- Now improving my Python skills and started some new projects.

